Michael Martinson

714 604 8818

michaelmartinson23@gmail.com

Orange County, CA

One year of experience as a Software Developer Engineer at Amazon. I am eager to learn something new and challenge myself. I am not scared of failure because I know failure is just an opportunity to learn and improve. If I lack knowledge to solve a problem I am confident that I can quickly gain the skills necessary to solve it. I would say that my strengths are: fast learner, persistent, hard worker, team player, passionate, optimistic, eager.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, University of Chicago Varsity Student-Athelete with Cumulative GPA 3.5/4.00

Honors: Dean's List, Academic All-Conference

Expected June 2021

Technical Skills

Language Proficiency

• Python, C, Javascript, HTML, CSS, React

Work Experience

Software Development Engineer Intern, Amazon

June 2020-August 2020

 Gained experience using Javascript, React, HTML, and CSS developing alexa skills.

Software Developer Intern, Center For Translational Data Science

June 2019-June 2020

• Gained experience using Python, Flask, and HTTP requests. Worked with a team using the Agile Framework

Projects

Python SDK - Center For Translational Data Science

 Created a software development kit for users and developers using gen3 data commons to hit a data commons api endpoints using python rather than using the UI

Project Cache - University of Chicago

• Built a C program to simulate a cache given number of sets, number of lines in each set, and block size then return the number of hits, misses, and evictions

Extracurricular

Varsity Football - University of Chicago, Running Back

August 2017-Present

 Balanced a 20+ hour weekly commitment to football with full academic course load. I developed skills in leadership, teamwork, time management, and resilience

Fellowship of Christian Athletes - University of Chicago, President/Member

October 2019-Present

• Coordinate and organize weekly meetings and club events. An example of an event that we run is blanket making for kids in childrens hospitals.

Interests

 Football, Board Games, Video Games, Cooking, Learning, Game Development, Hiking, Surfing Checkout my website to see a more indepth Resume: https://michael-martinson.github.io/me